Tushar Santosh Patil CYBERSECURITY ANALYST

Mumbai

Vikhroli, Mumbai

PROFILE

I am an Experienced SOC Analyst skilled in threat monitoring, incident response, and network security. Skilled in utilizing industry-standard tools to ensure network and system security. Strong collaborator with effective communication skills and a commitment to ongoing professional development in cybersecurity.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOC ANALYST Lvl 1 04/2023 - 05/2024

SAMAY INFOSOLUTION PVT LTD

- Performing real-time monitoring of security alerts and incidents.
- Implementing comprehensive SIEM tool for real-time security monitoring.
- Conducting initial analysis of security events and incidents.
- Utilizing log analysis tools to identify potential security threats.
- Managing and maintaining firewall configurations, specifically using Sophos.
- Implementing and overseeing Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR) solutions.
- Maintaining and updating asset information using Provconnect for effective asset management.
- Completing the installation of Fudo Security as a Privileged Access Management (PAM) tool
- Collaborating with team members to investigate and respond to security incidents.
- Staying informed about the latest security trends and vulnerabilities.
- Contributing to the enhancement of overall security policies and procedures.
- Providing timely and accurate reports on security incidents and activities.

INTERNSHIP

SECURITY ANALYST INTERN SAMAY INFOSOLUTION PVT LTD	01/2023 - 03/2023 Vikhroli, Mumbai
JUNIOR NETWORK ENGINEER C.S.INFOCOMM	05/2017 – 06/2017 Mulund, Mumbai

EDUCATION

B.E in Cyber Securtiy 2021 - 2024

Shah And Anchor Kutchhi Engineering College

Diploma in Computer Engineering 2017 - 2021

Government Polytechnic, Malvan

SKILLS

- SIEM (Seceon) Experience
- Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR) Experience
- Security Framework Knowledge
- Privileged access management (FUDO security)
- Firewall Configuration Basics
- Log Analysis And Threat Hunting Proficiency
- Asset Management

CERTIFICATES

ADVANCED PROGRAM IN FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Certificate Number: 22AAZZZZZ983

CERTIFIED ETHICAL HACKER (MASTER)

Certification Number: ECC3475982016

CERTIFIED PRACTICAL NETWORK PENETRATION TESTER™ (PNPT)

Certification Number: 101056624

ACHIEVEMENTS

SMART INDIA HACKATHON Competition Winner	12/2023
CERTIFIED SECEON PROFESSIONAL Certification ID: SECQ423106	10/2023
CERTIFIED SECEON PROFESSIONAL Certification ID: SECQ422429	05/2023
BEFOJJI OPSEC NGO Co-Lead Intern	12/2022
Anti Cyber Crime Society Anti-Phishing Volunteer	10/2022

PROJECTS

Lan-Based Examination System

• Developed a LAN-Based Examination System using Java for efficient examination processes.

Triple DES Encryption System

• Created a Triple DES Encryption System Desktop Application in Python to enhance data security.

Steganography

• Designed and implemented an Image Steganography Desktop Application in Python for concealing information within digital media.

INFOSINT

• Developed INFOSINT, a Python-based information gathering tool utilizing OSINT methodology.

ScanViz

• Developed ScanViz a Python-based tool for handling large Nmap output data efficiently.